# Alec Stone

Phone number 07729542007
Email alecdsstone@gmail.com
Portfolio alecstone.co.uk
LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/alecdsstone

#### **SUMMARY**

Highly Experienced C#, Unity3D and XR programmer with over a decade of work invested into 3D apps/games and web development, spanning multiple markets such as education, entertainment and e-commerce. Principled approach towards architecting systems, ensuring they are efficient, uncomplicated and maintainable. Critical thinker that approaches problems methodically. Employees under his management are set clear goals, while being provided with pedagogical support and counsel. Enjoys collaborating with and learning from interdisciplinary peers. Encouraged and excited about the maturing XR ecosystem.

#### **SKILLS**

- C#, Unity 3D
- Linear Algebra, Calculus
- Photon (PUN, Fusion)
- Readable, scalable, optimised code
- Architecting principled OOP systems with design patterns in mind
- Visual Studio, Rider
- ShaderLab, HLSL, SRP (All flavors), ShaderGraph
- Data Oriented Design, DOTS/ECS
- MRTK, Oculus XR, Unity XR, OVR
- Android, Quest 1/2, Windows MR, Hololens 1/2
- Jira (and other task trackers), Git, Plastic SCM

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### The Leadership Network

September 2021 - Present

Lead Engineer - Oculus Quest 2/Photon

- Lead Engineer for virtual reality corporate events company
- Implemented a number of high-volume multi-user gamified learning experiences
- Worked with high profile customers like Coca-Cola, Pfizer, Danone. Nestle
- Created components, tooling, and delivery pipelines to be used by other studio teams (Design/Art)

#### **Pauley Interactive**

May 2021 - September 2021

Senior Unity Developer - Microsoft Hololens 2

- Designing and developing "Two-Way" Digital Twins in AR.
- Building systems to consume and process real-time data from remote IoT devices hosted on Azure.
- Authoring code to control and add to an innovative Mixed
   Reality User Interface, with emphasis on simplicity and utility.

Alexander Stone 01/08/2022

 Designing and implementing tactile and responsive UI with a clear and inviting UX, utilising appropriate sound and visuals.

#### **Open University**

March 2020 - May 2021

Unity Developer - Oculus Quest

- Developed Educational simulation suite for nursing in VR.
- Designed and implemented many virtual nursing procedures.
- Faithfully recreated digital counterparts for real world items, sometimes emulating electronics devices and their behavior.
- Focused on pedagogical effectiveness through in-app analytics and feedback.

#### **Feed Optimise**

April 2018 - March 2020

Web Developer - E-Commerce Data Science

- Extracted, parsed and utilised data for eCommerce feeds.
- Built a network of internal web services and APIs.
- Contributed to development of proprietary data pipeline.
- Gained detailed understanding of back-end and dev ops technologies.
- Technical documentation written in aid of scalability and open source parts of the codebase..

#### TFA Marketing

June 2017 - April 2018

Full Stack Developer

- Lead front-end developer on the company's own website.
- Creating and maintaining bespoke websites using Laravel, LAMP, PHP, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery and Vue.
- Ported websites to platforms like Wordpress, Laravel and TFA's own CMS.

## Filmology - Sodexo

Feb 2017 - April 2017

Back-end Developer

- Used Python/Scrapy to acquire data on all cinemas in the UK.
- Took initiative to implement own solutions and architecture.
- Managed research and development into chosen technologies.

## **EDUCATION**

Continued Self-Driven Education

Ongoing

**CS50 Computer Science** 

October 2017 - Dec 2017

# **INTERESTS**

- I love playing games, especially technical marvels, or ones with great design
- I like to use Clojure and Rust in spare time
- Participate in game jams with community members.
- I like to play guitar and produce tracks

Alexander Stone 01/08/2022